<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter>
    <title>ITIL aligned service support with OTRS::ITSM</title>
    <para>
        Just like ITIL, OTRS::ITSM does not claim to be an
&quot;out-of-the-box&quot; solution for all tasks and questions arising in
IT service management. It is, in fact, supposed to serve as a flexible,
stable and easy to understand information platform that can be adapted to
meet the requirements of virtually every organization.

    </para>
    <para>
        Therefore, please excuse us for bringing the following to your attention:
The use of an ITIL aligned tool such as OTRS::ITSM only makes sense if
processes, people, and products (IT services) are truly ITIL aligned.
    </para>
    <para>
        Without the thoughtful tailoring of generic ITIL processes to meet the
requirements of the specific business scenario, OTRS::ITSM will not achieve
a discernible improvement of the key performance indicators of IT service
management.</para>
    <para>
        You should also be aware of the fact that successful ITIL implementation
projects typically take up to a year and longer. Their scope and impact on
the organization is not to be underestimated.  However, we would like to
mention that a neatly implemented ITIL aligned ITSM tool can help to save
time and money, as the process support of the tool aids and accelerates the
process of organizational realignment.
    </para>
    <para>
       Since version 2.0 , OTRS::ITSM supports the following features and
processes, which are usually designed during the first phase of an ITIL
implementation: Incident Management, Problem Management, Service Level
Management, Change Management and the Configuration Management Database.  A
more detailed description of use and adaptation of the system can be found
in the following sections. Please note that the each OTRS::ITSM package can
be installed independently and that their names correspond to their
respective ITIL topics.
    </para>
    <para>
        The implementation of OTRS::ITSM is based on ITIL v3.
    </para>
</chapter>
